A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, International Affairs, Office Files of Joseph E. Slater FA619
Rockefeller Archive Center
- ORGANIZATION FILES, 1957-1967; IV
  - International Broadcast Institute (IBI) - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1965 September-1967 July (Box 34, Folder 355-358)
    Includes correspondence to/from William Benton, Michel Gordey, Maurice Mitchell, Aurelio Peccei, and George Probst.
  - International Broadcast Institute (IBI) - Correspondence - Miscellaneous re: members, 1965 December-1967 October (Box 34, Folder 359-360)
  - International Broadcast Institute (IBI) - Correspondence - Webster, David, 1965 September-1967 September (Box 34, Folder 361)
  - International Broadcast Institute (IBI) - Meetings - Bellagio - Correspondence, 1965 December-1966 April (Box 35, Folder 362)
  - International Broadcast Institute (IBI) - Meetings - Bellagio - notes and agendas, 1966 January-March (Box 35, Folder 363)
  - International Broadcast Institute (IBI) - Meetings - Bellagio - Reports, 1966 February-March (Box 35, Folder 364)
  - International Broadcast Institute (IBI) - Meetings - Post-Bellagio, 1966 March-April, 1967 March-June (Box 35, Folder 365)
  - International Broadcast Institute (IBI) - Reports, 1965 December-1967 December (Box 35, Folder 366-369)
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), 1963 March-October, 1965 August-1966 October (Box 36, Folder 370-371)
    See also: Council on Foreign Relations, OECD study.
  - United Nations - Correspondence: Finklestein, Lawrence, 1962 August-October (Box 36, Folder 372)
    See also: Meeting Files (Series III), United Nations Policy Studies Program; Subject Files (Series V), Office of International Affairs.
  - United Nations - Miscellaneous, 1962-1967 (Box 36, Folder 373)
  - United Nations - Proposal: Peacekeeping in the Congo, 1963 October-1964 June (Box 36, Folder 374)
  - United Nations - Study: Finklestein, Lawrence, 1962 June-July (Box 36, Folder 375-376)
  - United Nations-affiliated organizations - International Labor Organization, 1963 September-1964 September (Box 36, Folder 377)
  - United Nations-affiliated organizations - U.N. International School, 1964 January, 1967 May (Box 36, Folder 378)
  - United Nations-affiliated organizations - UNA-USA, 1965 November-1967 September (Box 36, Folder 379)
  - United Nations-affiliated organizations - UNESCO, 1958 March-1966 January (Box 36, Folder 380)
    See also: Trip Notes (Series VI), 1958 February-March.
  - United Nations-affiliated organizations - UNITAR (United Nations Institute for Training and Research) - Correspondence - Casson, Peter, 1964 February (Box 36, Folder 381)
  - United Nations-affiliated organizations - UNITAR (United Nations Institute for Training and Research) - Correspondence - Cox, Arthur, 1963 December-1964 November (Box 36, Folder 382)
  - United Nations-affiliated organizations - UNITAR (United Nations Institute for Training and Research) - Correspondence - Finger, Seymour, 1963 October-1964 March (Box 36, Folder 383)
  - United Nations-affiliated organizations - UNITAR (United Nations Institute for Training and Research) - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1964 March-1967 October (Box 36, Folder 384)
  - United Nations-affiliated organizations - UNITAR (United Nations Institute for Training and Research) - Memoranda, notes, 1962 September-1967 October (Box 36, Folder 385)
- SUBJECT FILES, 1957-1967; V
  SUBJECT FILES are arranged in alphabetical order. Subject fies containing diverse material are arranged alphabetically by section. Office of International Affairs contains six sections, two of which - IA Program Review and OIR Self Study - are arranged in reverse chronological order.
  SERIES V, SUBJECT FILES (1957-1967), consists of 3.75 linear feet of reports, drafts, correspondence, memoranda, and notes. Reports, drafts, internal Foundation memoranda, and individual IA dockets (requests for grant action that were submitted to the Trustees for approval) which relate to program and budget planning of the IA program, are included in the subject files, Office of International Affairs. This subject also includes miscellaneous correspondence between Slater and individuals within and outside the Foundation. The miscellaneous correspondence is arranged alphabetically by individual or by his/her affiliated organization. Office of International Affairs also contains some memoranda of Richard Catalano (staff) and Charles McVicker (consultant). Office of International Affairs: miscellaneous notes, includes a memorandum (20 Mar 1961) by Waldemar Nielson on various IA program activities.
  - Arms Control - Correspondence - Finklestein, Lawrence, 1958 December-1963 October (Box 37, Folder 386)
  - Arms Control - Correspondence - King, James E., 1958 January-1960 June (Box 37, Folder 387)
  - Arms Control - Correspondence - Lefever, Ernest, 1960 February-1963 October (Box 37, Folder 388)
  - Arms Control - Correspondence - Leonard, L. Larry, 1958 January-1960 June (Box 37, Folder 389)
  - Arms Control - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1960 March-1962 March, 1963 March-1964 November (Box 37, Folder 390-391)
  - Arms Control - Correspondence - Rock, Vincent, 1962 December-1965 November (Box 37, Folder 392)
  - Arms Control - Economics of Arms Control, 1961 December-1962 March (Box 37, Folder 393)
  - Arms Control - Grenville Clark Project, 1958 April-May (Box 37, Folder 394)
  - Arms Control - Memoranda, notes, circa 1959 (Box 37, Folder 395)
  - Arms Control - Stevenson/Teeple Report - Correspondence, 1963 September-1964 November (Box 37, Folder 396)
  - Arms Control - Stevenson/Teeple Report - Distribution, commentary, 1963 December-1964 February (Box 37, Folder 397)
  - Citizen Education on World Affairs - Correspondence - Allen, Charles, 1964 July (Box 37, Folder 398)
  - Citizen Education on World Affairs - Correspondence - Huntley, James, 1966 January (Box 37, Folder 399)
  - Citizen Education on World Affairs - Correspondence - Nichols, Calvin, 1963 December-1965 May (Box 37, Folder 400)
  - Citizen Education on World Affairs - List of selected organizations, 1966 May (Box 37, Folder 401)
  - Civil Rights, 1965 March-1967 February (Box 37, Folder 402)
  - Communications, International, 1957 May-1967 May (Box 37, Folder 403)
    See also: Organization Files (Series IV), International Broadcast Institute.
  - Culture - Correspondence, 1957 August-1964 June (Box 38, Folder 404)
  - Culture - Memoranda, 1956 February-1958 February, 1962 May-1966 October (Box 38, Folder 405-406)
  - Culture - Miscellaneous - RGAs, docket excerpts, proposals, 1955 December-1964 December (Box 38, Folder 407)
  - Culture - Miscellaneous - Notes, undated (Box 38, Folder 408)
  - Education, 1965 June (Box 38, Folder 409)
  - English as a Second Language, 1962 February-1967 January (Box 38, Folder 410)
  - Ford Foundation, new building, 1963 July-1964 September (Box 38, Folder 411)
  - A Marshall Plan for Harlem, 1966 November-1976 April (Box 38, Folder 412)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, A-Z, 1961-1967 (Box 38, Folder 413-416)
  - Office of International Affairs - Breakdown of IA Grants, 1963 April-1966 September (Box 39, Folder 417)
  - Office of International Affairs - Budget, 1962 March-1963 February, 1966 March-1967 September (Box 39, Folder 418-420)
  - Office of International Affairs - Dockets - Fiscal Year 1966 (Box 40, Folder 421-423)
  - Office of International Affairs - Dockets - Fiscal Year 1965 (Box 40, Folder 424-425)
  - Office of International Affairs - Dockets - Fiscal Year 1964 (Box 40, Folder 426-427)
  - Office of International Affairs - Dockets - Fiscal Year 1963 (Box 41, Folder 428-430)
  - Office of International Affairs - Dockets - Fiscal Years 1961-1962 (Box 41, Folder 431-433)
  - Office of International Affairs - Dockets - 1959-1960 (Box 42, Folder 434-436)
  - Office of International Affairs - Dockets - 1956 (Box 42, Folder 437)
  - Office of International Affairs - General - Catalano, Richard: memoranda, 1965 January-1967 June (Box 43, Folder 438-439)
  - Office of International Affairs - General - McVicker, Charles: memoranda, 1966 May-1967 May (Box 43, Folder 440-442)
  - Office of International Affairs - General -Miscellaneous notes and grantee lists, 1957 January-1965 April (Box 43, Folder 443)
    Includes correspondence to/from William Benton.
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - OD self-study, Beirut, 1966 August-1967 April (Box 44, Folder 444)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - Commentary re strategy papers, 1966 December (Box 44, Folder 445)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - Strategy papers with commentary: Henry Kissinger, Robert Manning, 1966 November-December (Box 44, Folder 446-447)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - Reorganization, 1966 September-December (Box 44, Folder 448-449)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - Asia/Pacific, 1966 November (Box 44, Folder 450)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - Europe/Atlantic, 1966 November (Box 44, Folder 451)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - [IA administrator], 1966 November (Box 44, Folder 452)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - [IA concerns], 1966 November (Box 44, Folder 453)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - IA staff retreat: notes, 1966 November (Box 44, Folder 454)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - [proposals for U.N. and commentary on strategy paper: Lincoln Bloomfield], 1966 November (Box 44, Folder 455)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - [Proposals for U.N.: Elmore Jackson], 1966 November (Box 44, Folder 456)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - [Commentary re U.N. strategy paper: Porter McKeever], 1966 November (Box 44, Folder 457)
  - Office of International Affairs - IA Program Review - IA history: Walter Ashley, James Huntley, 1965 December-1966 April (Box 44, Folder 458)
  - Office of International Affairs - OIR [Office of International Relations] Self Study - Commentary on self study documents, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 459)
  - Office of International Affairs - OIR [Office of International Relations] Self Study -Reports, drafts (miscellaneous), 1967 March-September (Box 44, Folder 460)
  - Office of International Affairs - OIR [Office of International Relations] Self Study - Country statements, 1967 July (Box 44, Folder 461)
  - Office of International Affairs - OIR [Office of International Relations] Self Study - Program paper, 1967 July (Box 44, Folder 462)
    See also: November and December 1966 program papers.
  - Population, 1959 July (Box 45, Folder 463)
  - Public Service - Correspondence - McCloy, John, 1960 January (Box 45, Folder 464)
  - Public Service - Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1959 July-1960 August (Box 45, Folder 465)
    See also: Public Service - Proposals - Miscellaneous (folder 468).
  - Public Service - Proposals - Educational Leaves for Congressional Employees, 1965 May-June (Box 45, Folder 466)
  - Public Service - Proposals - Institute for International Service, 1961 November-1963 October (Box 45, Folder 467)
  - Public Service - Proposals - Miscellaneous, 1963 May, 1966 January-September (Box 45, Folder 468)
  - Science - Correspondence, 1963 April-1966 September (Box 45, Folder 469)
  - Science - Drafts, correspondence, 1962 September-1963 August (Box 45, Folder 470)
  - Science - Memoranda, notes, 1962 May-1966 September (Box 45, Folder 471)
- TRIP NOTES, 1957-1967; VI
  TRIP NOTES are arranged in reverse chronological order by the inclusive dates of each trip. Within each trip, the places visited are aranged in alphabetical order. Within each folder, the material is arranged in reverse chronological order.
  The trip notes of Richard Catalano, Stanley Gordon, Waldemar Nielson, and Shepard Stone are arranged in alphabetical order at the end of the series. The material within each folder is arranged in reverse chronological order.
  SERIES VI, TRIP NOTES (1957-1967), consists of 1.25 linear feet of itineraries, correspondence, memoranda and notes. This material should be used in conjunction with Series II, GEOGRAHIC FILES. The material from Slater's earlier (1958 and 1959) trips to Europe are the most extensively documented. The trip notes of Richard Catalano, Stanley Gordon, Waldemar Nielson, and Shepard Stone are filed separately at the end of the series.
  - Europe trip, 1967 May-June - Munich, Berlin, Paris - notes (Box 46, Folder 472)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Australia, New Zealand - Appointments, notes (Box 46, Folder 473)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Australia, New Zealand - Correspondence, 1966 May-June (Box 46, Folder 474)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Australia, New Zealand - Memoranda (Box 46, Folder 475)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Hong Kong - Notes, 1966 June-August (Box 46, Folder 476)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Japan - Appointments, 1966 July (Box 46, Folder 477)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Japan - Center for Southeast Asian Studies, 1966 May-July (Box 46, Folder 478)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Japan - Correspondence, 1965 November-1966 July (Box 46, Folder 479)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Japan - Memoranda, 1966 July (Box 46, Folder 480)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Japan - Notes, 1966 July (Box 46, Folder 481)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Korea - Appointments (Box 46, Folder 482)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Korea - Correspondence (Box 46, Folder 483)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Korea - Memorandum, notes, 1966 July (Box 46, Folder 484)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1966 June-July - Taiwan - Correspondence (Box 46, Folder 485)
  - Europe trip, 1966 February - Switzerland, London - Appointments, correspondence, 1965 November-1966 February (Box 46, Folder 486)
  - Europe trip, January 1965 - Berlin - Notes, correspondence, 1964 December-1965 January (Box 46, Folder 487)
  - Europe trip, January 1965 - London, Paris, Berlin - Itinerary, appointments, 1965 January (Box 46, Folder 488)
  - Europe trip, January 1965 - Paris - Memoranda, 1965 January (Box 46, Folder 489)
  - Europe trip, 1965 June-July - London - Appointments, correspondence (Box 46, Folder 490)
  - Europe trip, 1965 June-July - Paris - Appointments (Box 46, Folder 491)
  - Europe trip, 1965 June-July - Atlantic Institute/Young Leaders Project (Box 46, Folder 492)
    See also: Organization Files (Series IV), Atlantic Institute; Geographic Files (Series II), Europe/Atlantic, Young Leaders Project.
  - Europe and Soviet Union trip, 1964 August-October - Itinerary (Box 46, Folder 493)
  - Europe and Soviet Union trip, 1964 August-October - Berlin - Appointments, 1964 September (Box 46, Folder 494)
  - Europe and Soviet Union trip, 1964 August-October - Bucharest/Budapest - Correspondence, memoranda, background, 1964 August-September (Box 46, Folder 495)
  - Europe and Soviet Union trip, 1964 August-October - Italy - Appointments, background material, 1964 May-October (Box 46, Folder 496)
  - Europe and Soviet Union trip, 1964 August-October - Moscow - Correspondence (Box 46, Folder 497)
  - Europe and Soviet Union trip, 1964 August-October - Correspondence, post-trip, 1964 October-1965 August (Box 46, Folder 498)
  - Europe and Soviet Union trip, 1964 August-October - Slater/Shulman (Mrs. Colette) notes (Box 46, Folder 499)
  - Europe trip, 1964 January - Background material, 1963 May-August (Box 46, Folder 500)
  - Europe trip, 1964 January - London, Paris - Appointments (Box 46, Folder 501)
  - Europe trip, 1964 January - London - Correspondence, memoranda, 1963 May-1964 January (Box 46, Folder 502)
  - Europe trip, 1964 January - Paris - Correspondence, notes, 1963 December-1964 January (Box 46, Folder 503)
  - Europe trip, 1964 January - Paris - Maison des Sciences de l'Homme (Box 46, Folder 504)
  - Europe trip, 1964 January - Spain - Correspondence, 1963 April-1964 September (Box 46, Folder 505)
  - Washington trip, 1964 - Appointments: 11-12 November 1964, 22 June 1964, 30 April-4 May 1964 (Box 46, Folder 506)
    See also: Meeting Files (Series III), Meetings: NAS Committee for Science Cooperation, Taiwan.
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1963 September - Japan - Correspondence, 1962 September-1963 January (Box 47, Folder 507)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1963 September - Japan - Memoranda, notes (Box 47, Folder 508)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1962 September-November - Correspondence, 1962 September-October (Box 47, Folder 509)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1962 September-November - Itineraries, undated (Box 47, Folder 510)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1962 September-November - Australia, Hawaii - Memoranda, 1962 October (Box 47, Folder 511)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1962 September-November - Hong Kong - Correspondence, notes, 1962 October-November (Box 47, Folder 512)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1962 September-November - India - Correspondence, notes (Box 47, Folder 513)
  - Asia/Pacific trip, 1962 September-November - Japan - Memoranda, 1962 October (Box 47, Folder 514)
  - Europe trip, 1960 April-June - Background material, 1958 December-1960 March (Box 47, Folder 515)
  - Europe trip, 1960 April-June - Correspondence, 1960 March-May (Box 47, Folder 516)
  - Europe trip, 1960 April-June - Itineraries (Box 47, Folder 517)
  - Europe trip, 1960 April-June - Memoranda (Box 47, Folder 518)
  - Europe trip, 1960 April-June - Post-trip notes, memoranda, 1960 June-November (Box 47, Folder 519)
  - Europe trip, 1960 April-June - Great Britain - Background material, 1960 February-May (Box 47, Folder 520)
  - Europe trip, 1960 April-June - Helsinki - Background material, 1960 April-May (Box 47, Folder 521)
  - Europe trip, 1960 April-June - The Netherlands - Background material, 1959 February-December (Box 47, Folder 522)
  - Europe trip, 1960 April-June - Yugoslavia - Background material, 1959 October-1960 April (Box 47, Folder 523)
  - Europe trip, 1960 April-June - Yugoslavia - Notes (Box 47, Folder 524)
  - Europe trip, 1959 May-June - Itineraries, 1959 April (Box 47, Folder 525)
    See also: Chronological Files (Series I), European trip, 1959 May-June.
  - Europe trip, 1959 May-June - Basel, Switzerland - Memoranda (Box 47, Folder 526)
  - Europe trip, 1959 May-June - Belgium - Memoranda, 1959 June (Box 47, Folder 527)
  - Europe trip, 1959 May-June - France - Memoranda, 1959 June (Box 47, Folder 528)
  - Europe trip, 1959 May-June - Germany (Berlin, Bonn) - Memoranda (Box 47, Folder 529)
  - Europe trip, 1959 May-June - London - Memoranda, 1959 June (Box 47, Folder 530)
  - Europe trip, 1959 May-June - Rome - Memoranda (Box 47, Folder 531)
  - Europe trip, 1958 February-March - Background material, 1957 September-December (Box 47, Folder 532)
  - Europe trip, 1958 February-March - Correspondence, 1958 January-March (Box 47, Folder 533)
  - Europe trip, 1958 February-March - Itinerary (Box 47, Folder 534)
  - Europe trip, 1958 February-March - Memoranda (Box 47, Folder 535)
  - Europe trip, 1958 February-March - Post-trip correspondence, 1958 February-April (Box 47, Folder 536)
  - Richard Catalano trip files, 1966
    - Europe trip, 1966 - London, Paris, Geneva, Barcelona - Memoranda, appointments, 1966 April-July (Box 48, Folder 537)
  - Stanley Gordon trip files, 1959
    - Europe trip, 1959 - Bologna - Memoranda, 1959 November (Box 48, Folder 538)
    - Europe trip, 1959 - Frankfurt - Memoranda, 1959 November (Box 48, Folder 539)
    - Europe trip, 1959 - The Hague - Memoranda, 1959 October (Box 48, Folder 540)
    - Europe trip, 1959 - Helsinki - Memoranda, 1959 October (Box 48, Folder 541)
    - Europe trip, 1959 - London - Memoranda, 1959 October (Box 48, Folder 542)
    - Europe trip, 1959 - Oslo - Memoranda, 1959 October (Box 48, Folder 543)
    - Europe trip, 1959 - Paris - Memoranda, 1959 October (Box 48, Folder 544)
  - Waldemar Nielsen trip files, 1959
    - Europe trip, 1959 - Athens, Greece - Memoranda, 1959 June-July (Box 48, Folder 545)
  - Shepard Stone trip files, 1957, 1959
    - Europe trip, 1959 - Brussels - Memoranda, 1959 October (Box 48, Folder 546)
    - Europe trip, 1959 - London - Memoranda, 1959 October (Box 48, Folder 547)
    - Europe trip, 1959 - Paris - Memorandum, 1959 October (Box 48, Folder 548)
    - Europe trip, 1959 - Rome - Memoranda, 1959 October (Box 48, Folder 549)
    - Europe trip, 1957 - Background material for speech, 1957 October-November (Box 48, Folder 550)